<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Automatically destroy poops and fires (and sometimes rocks and secret room walls)</name>
    <directory>automatically_destroy_poops_and_fires</directory>
    <id>2955338644</id>
    <description>[h2]Description[/h2]
In rooms with no enemies, this mod automatically destroys fires and poops, and all obstacles and secret room walls if you could destroy them without spending bombs. It saves a lot of time as you don't need to &quot;farm&quot; poops and fires anymore, or manually look for secret rooms and trapdoors. It does make it much easier to reach the boss rush and Hush, so if you're worried about balance you can enable the mod in the options after you're reached them.

[h2]Options[/h2]
The mod can be configured using Mod Config Menu Pure https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2681875787.

In the configuration menu you can:
[list]
    [*] enable/disable the destruction of specific types of fires, poops, rocks and walls. By default, only normal fires, normal poops and golden poops are destroyed.
    [*] enable/disable the mod entirely (without having to go back to the main menu!), or only enable it after 20 minutes/boss rush or 30 minutes/Hush.
[/list]

[h2]Obstacle destruction[/h2]
[h3]Poops and fires[/h3]
All poops and fires are destroyed in empty rooms, even if you can't reach them (if they're behind a wall for example). It *can* give you an advantage in some rare situations, because broken poops behind unpassable walls can drop loot that you can then decide to pick up using a The Hangman card for example. Destroyed poops automatically fill holes around them.

[h3]Rocks[/h3]
Like with poop destruction, rocks are destroyed even if unreachable, *but* only you could destroy them without spending a bomb: if have a golden bomb, or if you are stompy, or if you have a passive item that would allow you to destroy them (i.e. all items that turn your tears into bombs or create bombs for free, Sulfuric Acid, and Samson's Chains). Destroyed rocks will automatically fill holes all around them.

[h3]Pots, skulls and mushrooms[/h3]
Pots and skulls are destroyed only if you could destroy them safely from afar, therefore they're not destroyed if you're only stompy or only have Samson's Chains  (Pots can spawn spiders than hurt you instantly, mushrooms can explode). If you can destroy them safely, Spiders and Hosts spawned by destroyed pots and skulls will be killed instantly, and destroyed mushrooms and rock bombs won't hurt you.

[h3]D12 and Mom's Bracelet[/h3]
The D12 and Mom's Bracelet can make obstacles useful, therefore their automatic destruction is disabled by default when you have these items equipped. It can be enabled in the options.

If you have Mom's Bracelet equipped, and enable obstacle destruction in the options, all obstacles will be destroyed automatically.

[h3]Secret room entrances[/h3]
If you could destroy secret room entrances without spending bombs, the entrances will be open (you get the &quot;I can see forever&quot; pill effect).</description>
    <version>0.10</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
